Today we're going to be walking through how to use DeepSeek v3 in n8n
今日はn8nでDeepSeek v3を使う方法について説明します。
for a fraction of what it costs to use something like GPT-4o or Claude 3.5 Sonnet.
GPT-4oやClaude 3.5 Sonnetといったモデルを使うよりも、はるかに安価です。
But real quick, what is DeepSeek v3?
まず、DeepSeek v3について簡単に説明します。
It's an open source model that was recently released
DeepSeek v3は、最近リリースされたオープンソースモデルです。
and it pretty much outperforms every other open source model out there.
現存する他のオープンソースモデルよりも優れた性能を発揮します。
And it also performs pretty comparable to the leading
また、最先端のクローズドソースモデルである
closed source models like GPT-4o.
GPT-4oにも引けを取らない性能を誇ります。
Now, I'm not an expert on models and fine tuning and training and all that kind of stuff,
私はモデル、ファインチューニング、トレーニングなどの専門家ではありません。
but I've got a couple of graphics that I'll walk through here
ですが、いくつかのグラフを使って説明します。
and I'll also include the link to the technical report
また、技術レポートへのリンクも概要欄に貼っておきますので、
in the description if you guys want to check it out for yourself.
ご自身で確認してみてください。
So as you can see right here in the blue,
この青い部分がDeepSeekです。
And it's pretty much outperforming all of them in these six metrics.
DeepSeekはこれら6つの指標すべてで、他のモデルより優れています。
But why did I decide to make this video and why did you probably click on it?
では、なぜ私がこの動画を作成し、皆さんがこの動画をクリックしたのでしょうか？
Because of the price.
それは価格です。
So as you can see here in the green, we've got $0.014 per million tokens.
この緑色の部分を見ると、100万トークンあたり0.014ドルであることが分かります。
So you can just throw something like $2 in there and it's going to get you a really, really long way.
2ドル程度の投資で、本当に長い間使える量です。
Here's another graphic from that report that I was talking about.
先ほどお話しした技術レポートに含まれている、もう一つのグラフをお見せします。
This is the needle in the haystack test.
これは「干し草の山から針を探す」テストです。
As you can see, the whole board is green.
ご覧の通り、全体が緑色で表示されています。
So, perfect 10 out of 10 score across everything.
つまり、すべての項目で10点満点中10点を獲得したということです。
This basically tells us that DeepSeek v3 is really, really good with its context length
これは、DeepSeek v3がコンテキストの長さを処理するのに非常に優れていることを示しています。
and understanding everything that's going through and not
すべての内容を理解し、他のモデルのように
missing out any information the way that some other models might.
情報を見落とすことがないということです。
So, something really interesting about DeepSeek
DeepSeek v3の興味深い点は、
v3 is that it uses a mixture of experts model.
混合エキスパートモデル（Mixture of Experts）を採用していることです。
Rather than having one model across all the parameters,
すべてのパラメータに対して一つのモデルを使うのではなく、
this one has sub-models that it can sort of send out based on
特定の分野に対する専門知識に基づいて、
expertise in certain areas, which is pretty cool.
複数のサブモデルを選択的に活用する方式です。
Once again, it's not something I fully understand as far as all the technicalities.
繰り返しになりますが、私もすべての技術的な内容を完璧に理解しているわけではありません。
Go check out that report if you want to read more about it.
詳細は技術レポートをご覧ください。
But this isn't me recommending that it's
これは、私がDeepSeek v3を推奨したり、使用を勧めたりするものではありません。
And of course, you should be careful with the data that you're putting into something like DeepSeek v3.
もちろん、DeepSeek v3のようなモデルにデータを入力する際には注意が必要です。
But I just kind of wanted to bring you the facts of what I know and
私は、私が知っている事実とn8nへの接続方法、
how to actually plug it into n8n and just get in there and play around with it a little bit.
そして、実際に使ってみた感想をお伝えしたかっただけです。
So, let's get into n8n.
では、n8nに移りましょう。
So, today I'm going to be talking about two ways to connect DeepSeek v3 into n8n.
今日は、DeepSeek v3をn8nに接続する2つの方法を紹介します。
So, the first one is hooking it up as the brain for your AI agent.
1つ目は、AIエージェントの頭脳、つまりチャットモデルとして接続する方法です。
The chat model for your AI agent.
AIエージェントのチャットモデルとして使用するのです。
As you can see right here, it looks like we're connecting to an OpenAI chat model.
ここでは、OpenAIのチャットモデルに接続しているように見えますが、
But if you click in, you can see that we're actually using
詳しく見ると、実際には
an OpenRouter base URL to point us to DeepSeek chat.
OpenRouterのベースURLを使用して、DeepSeekチャットに接続しています。
So, that's what's going on here.
これが1つ目の方法です。
And then the second way is to use it as sort of its own node,
2つ目の方法は、DeepSeek v3を独立したノードとして使う方法です。
like a OpenAI message and model node.
OpenAIのメッセージとモデルノードのようにです。
So, as you can see here, we're doing a post request to DeepSeek
ここでは、DeepSeekにPOSTリクエストを送信し、
and we're sending in information for it to come back with a response.
情報を渡して応答を受け取る方式です。
So, I'll real quickly show off these two methods and then we'll get into how you actually do it.
では、この2つの方法を簡単に試した後、実際にどのように設定するのかを説明します。
So, first we'll do this one.
まず、この方法から試してみましょう。
As you can see here, it's a post request to DeepSeek.
ご覧の通り、DeepSeekにPOSTリクエストを送信しています。
We have our stuff that I'll show you guys how to configure.
設定方法は後ほど詳しく説明します。
And then pretty much in here, what we're asking it to do is we're sending,
ここでは、「次のトピックに関するFacebookの投稿を作成して」というリクエストを送信しています。
write me a Facebook post about the following topic.
トピックは動的に設定され、
The topic's dynamic based on what we put into this set node right here,
このノードに入力した値によって決まります。
which is health and fitness in 2025.
今は「2025年の健康とフィットネス」に設定されています。
So, let's fire this off real quick.
では、実行してみましょう。
As you can see, it's hitting DeepSeek and then it's going to come back to us with a result,
DeepSeekにリクエストを送信し、応答を待ちます。
which should be a formatted Facebook post
応答は、絵文字とハッシュタグを含む形式のFacebook投稿になります。
As you can see, health and fitness, the future is here.
ご覧の通り、「健康とフィットネス、未来はここに」というタイトルと、
It's got a couple points and then it ends with a nice little motivational message.
いくつかの内容があり、最後にはモチベーションを高めるメッセージで締めくくられています。
And if this is confusing to you,
この部分は分かりにくいかもしれませんが、
it's the exact same way that you would set up an OpenAI message and model node.
OpenAIのメッセージとモデルノードを設定するのと全く同じ方法です。
And you've probably done that multiple times.
おそらく皆さんは、すでに何度も試したことがあるでしょう。
You've got a system role right here, which is
ここで、システムロールはこのノードが何をするかを定義するものです。
We're just saying you're a helpful assistant.
「あなたは役立つアシスタントです」と設定しました。
And then we have the actual user role, which is what we want it to take and do,
そして、ユーザーロールはこのノードに何をさせるか、つまり私たちが望むタスクを定義します。
which is writing a Facebook post about health and fitness in 2025.
ここでは、「2025年の健康とフィットネスに関するFacebook投稿の作成」をリクエストしています。
So, if that's confusing, just look at it like this, right?
この部分が分かりにくい場合は、このように考えてください。
In OpenAI, usually you're set up your different messages.
OpenAIでは通常、複数のメッセージを設定します。システムロールとユーザーロールがあります。
So, right here, helpful assistant, write me a Facebook post.
ここでは、「役立つアシスタント」、「Facebook投稿の作成」と設定しました。
And it's pretty much the exact same thing coming through.
そして、この2つはほぼ同じように動作します。
So, that's pretty much all that's going on here.
違いをお見せするために、完了するまで待ちます。
I just wanted to let this finish so we could see the difference.
この部分は完了するまで待ってから、違いをお見せします。
There we go. So, this was using 4o.
完了しました。これは4oを使った結果です。
And this one, again, is
そして、この結果は、
a little bit different because it uses a different model, but same aspect of Facebook post.
別のモデルを使ったため少し異なりますが、Facebook投稿という同じ目的を持っています。
Anyways, now we'll come up here and we'll pretty much do that same thing.
では、上の例を実行してみましょう。
So... this is connected to...
この例はDeepSeek v3に接続されています。
what's it called? DeepSeek v3. And we'll do the same thing.
DeepSeek v3に接続して、同じリクエストをしてみましょう。
Make a Facebook post
Facebook投稿の作成
about health and fitness 2025.
2025年の健康とフィットネス
And... okay.
そして...
So, we actually didn't connect our credential real quick.
資格情報を接続していませんでした。
We were connected to our OpenAI account, but as you can see, I have a different credential here,
以前はOpenAIアカウントに接続していましたが、今はDeepSeekの資格情報を使っています。
which is the DeepSeek one. So, I'll show you guys how to set this up.
資格情報の設定方法は後ほど説明します。
But now this should work fine.
これで正常に動作するはずです。
Let's go back in here, send that off.
戻って、リクエストを送信してみましょう。
And I know it's a little confusing because it looks like it's still an OpenAI chat model,
まだOpenAIのチャットモデルのように見えるので、分かりにくいかもしれませんが、
but like I said, all we have to do is grab an API key from OpenRouter
先ほどお話ししたように、OpenRouterでAPIキーを取得するだけで、
and then we'll be good to go to set everything up.
すべての設定が完了します。
Okay. There we go.
はい、できました。
So, now we got our Facebook post back.
これでFacebook投稿が作成されました。
Very similar with its
前の例と非常によく似ていて、
hashtags at the end, with its different emojis for different sections.
最後にハッシュタグがあり、各セクションに絵文字が使われています。
And yeah.
はい、できました。
So, those are the two use cases that we're going to walk over real quick.
ここまで、2つの使用例を簡単に見てきました。
So, let's hop into DeepSeek and set everything up.
では、DeepSeekの設定方法を見ていきましょう。
Okay. So, you're going to go to DeepSeek.com.
まず、DeepSeek.comにアクセスします。
You'll come into this screen. You'll sign in or you'll create an account.
この画面でログインするか、アカウントを作成します。
And then you're going to click on access API.
そして、「Access API」をクリックします。
So, this is going to take you straight to your API settings. So,
すると、API設定ページに移動します。
it took me to my usage. As you can see, I put in $2.
私は使用量ページに移動しました。ご覧の通り、私は2ドルをチャージしました。
I've got over 7 million tokens.
700万以上のトークンを使用できます。
You're going to click on API keys, create new key.
「API keys」をクリックし、「create new key」をクリックします。
We'll call this one demo.
名前を「demo」にします。
And then you want to copy that and paste it somewhere safe
そして、生成されたAPIキーをコピーして、安全な場所に貼り付けてください。
because you won't be able to re-access it.
後で再び見ることはできないからです。
And you could always just create a new one, but
もちろん、新しいキーを再生成することもできますが、
best practice is to paste it somewhere safe.
安全な場所に貼り付けておくのが最善です。
Then you need to make sure you have some tokens available. So, just add in like $2.
次に、使用可能なトークンがあることを確認します。2ドル程度チャージしてください。
And then you want to click on docs down here on the left side.
そして、左下の「docs」をクリックします。
This is going to bring you to this API documentation.
すると、APIドキュメントページに移動します。
And all you have to do is scroll down right here. We've got a curl.
下にスクロールすると、curlの例があります。
We're going to copy this curl
このcurlをコピーします。
and it's going to be super easy. We'll hop back into n8n.
あとは、n8nに戻って貼り付けるだけです。
As you can see, there's currently no DeepSeek integration.
現在、n8nにはDeepSeekの統合機能はありません。
So, what we have to do is grab an HTTP request.
そのため、HTTPリクエストノードを使う必要があります。
And all we have to do is import curl and paste that right in there.
「import curl」をクリックし、先ほどコピーしたcurlを貼り付けます。
So, as you can see, it's going to change it to a post request.
すると、POSTリクエストに自動的に変更されます。
It put in the correct endpoint
正しいエンドポイントが入力され、
and has our header already, which is our authorization.
認証情報を含むヘッダーも自動的に入力されました。
And then it has our JSON already filled out. So, super easy.
そして、JSONデータもすでに埋め込まれています。非常に簡単です。
Now, what you want to do is you got to go grab that API key.
次に、先ほどコピーしておいたAPIキーを取得します。
And then you want to get rid of this.
そして、この部分を削除します。
It's going to be bearer space your API key.
「Bearer」の後にスペースを1つ入れ、APIキーを貼り付けます。
And then make sure there's no extra leading or trailing white space as well.
そして、前後に不要なスペースがないように注意してください。
And that should work.
これで正常に動作するはずです。
So, right now, what we're sending over is the prompt is hello to a helpful assistant.
現在、「役立つアシスタントにhello」というプロンプトを送信しています。
We'll just hit test step to make sure everything's working.
「test step」をクリックし、すべてが正常に動作することを確認してみましょう。
And as you can see, we got back, hello, how can I assist you today?
「こんにちは、今日は何をお手伝いしましょうか？」という応答が返ってきました。
So, it was responding to the message, which was hello.
「hello」というメッセージに対する応答です。
So, that's pretty much it.
設定はほぼ完了です。
At this point, you would set up, you know, you could prompt
あとは、このDeepSeekノードに
this deep seek node a little differently if you wanted it to do something more specific.
別のプロンプトを設定することで、より具体的なタスクを実行させることができます。
And then you could dynamically give the information that you want it to respond to.
そして、応答を、望む情報を動的に提供するようにもできます。
Okay. Now, to set up a chat model.
では、チャットモデルを設定してみましょう。
So, let's delete this one.
このノードは削除します。
We're going to add another one, which is an OpenAI chat model.
OpenAIのチャットモデルノードを追加します。
And this is like the default way that it pretty much opens up.
これは基本的に開かれる方法です。
And we need to create a new credential.
新しい資格情報を作成する必要があります。
But before that, we need to set up everything with open router.
ですが、その前に、OpenRouterですべてを設定する必要があります。
So, we're going to click add option.
「add option」をクリックします。
We're going to add a base URL.
「base URL」を追加します。
Default, of course, it points to OpenAI because that's the model we're grabbing.
基本的にはOpenAIを指していますが、これは私たちが取得しようとしているモデルだからです。
But we're going to go to open router.
では、OpenRouterに移動します。
You'll create an account.
アカウントを作成します。
And then all we need to do is go to deep seek v3.
そして、DeepSeek v3を探します。
What we want to do here is click on API.
ここで「API」をクリックします。
And we're looking for a base URL to point to, to grab deep seek.
DeepSeekを取得するために指定するベースURLを探す必要があります。
So, we're going to grab this right here.
ここの部分をコピーします。
Base URL within the quotations.
引用符の中のベースURLをコピーします。
Copy that.
再びn8nに戻ります。
Go back into n8n.
ここに貼り付けます。これで、
Paste that in there. So, now we're
OpenRouterのベースURLにアクセスしています。
accessing the base URL of open router.
そして、上部のGPT-4o miniの代わりに、
And then up here, instead of accessing GPT-4o mini,
または、使用している他のモデルの代わりに、「expression」を選択します。既存のモデル名を消去します。
You're going to get rid of that.
再びOpenRouterに戻ります。
Go back into open router.
DeepSeek v3のページであることを確認します。
And make sure you're on deep seek v3.
ここの部分をコピーします。
You're going to copy that right here.
モデル名をコピーします。deepseek/deepseek-chat
And then you're going to paste that in there.
そして、ここに貼り付けます。
So, now we're pointing to open router URL, which is grabbing this model of deep seek.
これで、OpenRouterのURLを通じて、DeepSeekのこのモデルにアクセスしています。
And now before we...
では、
Hit out of here. We need to create new credentials.
次に進む前に、新しい資格情報を作成する必要があります。
So, you can see I've got a deep seek credential. I'm going to create a new one.
ご覧の通り、私はDeepSeekの資格情報を持っています。新しい資格情報を作成してみましょう。
But first, we need to create an API key.
ですが、まずAPIキーを作成する必要があります。
So, you're already in this page.
すでにこのページにいます。
You're going to click create API key.
「create API key」をクリックします。
You're going to create key.
「create a key」をクリックします。
Name it whatever you want.
好きな名前を付けます。
And then same thing as always.
そして、先ほどと同様に、
Copy this into somewhere safe.
このキーを安全な場所にコピーしておきます。
And then you're pretty much just going to go back into n8n.
そして、n8nに戻ります。
Hit create new credential.
「create new credential」をクリックします。
And paste your API key right into here.
そして、ここにAPIキーを貼り付けます。
Once you do that, you're going to hit save.
その後、「save」をクリックします。
In the bottom right, it's going to go green and say, So it's currently private to you
右下に「現在は非公開です」という緑色のメッセージが表示されます。
and right here it's going to go red.
そして、ここは赤色に変わります。
Not exactly sure why it does that, but
なぜそうなるのか正確には分かりませんが、
you're connected if you get the green down here.
下に緑色のメッセージが表示されれば、接続は完了しています。
That might just be a bug, but we're good to go.
バグかもしれませんが、とにかく接続は完了しました。
So we've got our API key from OpenRouter set up right here.
OpenRouterで作成したAPIキーがここに設定されました。
We have the DeepSeek model that we want,
使用したいDeepSeekモデルを選択し、
and then we have OpenRouter being able to access this model for us.
OpenRouterがこのモデルにアクセスできるように設定しました。
So now we just want to test to make sure it's working.
では、正常に動作するかテストしてみましょう。
We're going to open up a chat and we'll do this again, but instead of health and fitness,
チャットを開き、もう一度テストしてみましょう。 今回は「健康とフィットネス」ではなく「スポーツ」に
what it says here.
設定してみましょう。
And as you can see, it's hitting the model right now, which is obviously DeepSeek,
ご覧の通り、現在はDeepSeekモデルにリクエストを送信しています。
even though it looks like OpenAI.
OpenAIのように見えますが。
And we know that it's working because it would have already failed by now if we didn't have it set up.
そして、正常に動作していることが分かります。設定が間違っていれば、すでに失敗しているはずです。
As you saw earlier, it failed really quick.
先ほどご覧いただいたように、設定が間違っていると、非常に早く失敗します。
Okay, so it just popped through.
はい、応答が返ってきました。
We've got sports in 2025 where innovation meets passion.
「革新と情熱が出会う、2025年のスポーツ」というタイトルと共に、
Again, emojis, little things.
絵文字と内容が表示されています。
And remember, this is zero prompting at all, but then it ends with some hashtags.
そして、ここでは全くプロンプトエンジニアリングをしていませんが、最後にハッシュタグで締めくくられています。
But yeah, like I said, there's no prompting going on in here.
ですが、お話ししたように、ここでは何のプロンプトエンジニアリングも適用していません。
But this is, of course, the chat input that I got and our output.
これは私が入力したチャット内容で、その結果です。
So that's pretty much going to be it for this one.
今回の動画はここで終わりにします。
I know it wasn't too complex, but I just wanted to show you guys how you can access this stuff
それほど複雑な内容ではありませんでしたが、皆さんが実際に試せるように、
so you can get in there and start playing around with it.
これらの機能をどのように活用できるかをお見せしたかったのです。
I'm definitely going to play around with a little bit more, some complex agents
私は今後、DeepSeekモデルを使って、
with our DeepSeek model and just seeing how it reacts to them
もう少し複雑なエージェントを作成し、
using different tools and stuff.
様々なツールを使った時にどのように反応するかを見ていく予定です。
But two credits in DeepSeek, five credits in OpenRouter.
DeepSeekに2クレジット、OpenRouterに5クレジットを使ってみてください。
In OpenRouter, you have a ton of different models you can access as well,
OpenRouterでは様々なモデルを使うことができます。
but those credits will get you a long way for sure. But yeah, as always, if you found this one helpful,
この程度のクレジットがあれば、十分に長い間使えるはずです。今回の動画が役に立ったなら、いいねを押してください。本当に大きな力になります。
please give it a like, definitely helps me out.
動画が役に立ったなら、いいねをぜひ押してください。本当に大きな力になります。
Great to be back.
戻ってくることができて嬉しいです。
Hope you guys all had a happy new year.
皆さん、良いお年を迎えられたことを願っています。
I'm really excited to see what 2025 brings as far as the channel,
私のチャンネルとAI分野など、すべての面で2025年がどのような年になるか、本当に楽しみです。
the AI space, all that kind of stuff.
AI分野を含め、すべてにおいて、2025年がどのような姿になるのか、本当に楽しみです。
And definitely let me know in the comments what else you guys are looking to see
今後数週間、数ヶ月、そして来年にどのような動画を見たいか、コメント欄で教えてください。
in the next few weeks, in the next few months, and in the next year.
今後数週間、数ヶ月、そして来年にどのような動画を見たいか、コメントで教えてください。
So thanks for making it to the end of this one, guys.
最後までご覧いただき、ありがとうございました。